Matthew Sandor

New Canaan, Connecticut | 203-800-1272 | matthewsandor01@gmail.com LinkedIn | Github | Blog

FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Software Engineer with experience with Python with Flask, and JavaScript based programming and a background in Godot/Java. Possess strong skills in communication, and problem solving. Known for a positive attitude and out of the box thinking when approaching projects.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Python with Flask, SQL, JavaScript, React, Godot, Java, node js, obs, Adobe Animate

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Character Creation - Github | Demo

App that allows users to create account login, edit/delete unique characters and view friends' creations.

- Developed front end with React and Bootstrap to create a seamless and interactive user interface
- Employed Python to create a database schema with both one-to-many and many-to-many relationships
- Implemented full CRUD functionality for seamless communication between front end and back end.
- Employed cookies to ensure persistent user login sessions and to retain selected character preferences across different pages.

Time Clock - Github | Demo

App that lets non-admin users clock-in/out with admin functionality to let admins add/remove users and see all user data

- Utilized Python to create a command line interface program for the end user
- Acquired user key inputs to inform user actions such as clocking in/out
- Employed SQL to store data in database tables for userdata creation and deletion

Coffee Shop - Github | Demo

Webpage that lets users see a menu of a variety of coffee available for purchase as well as add/remove coffee

- Customized CSS front end to create flexible UI elements for users
- Handled local data storage via db.json file to store locally available data
- Enhanced the user interface of web page by implementing forms with text and image input for Item creation

EXPERIENCE

Walter Stewart's Market

Deli Worker

New Canaan, Connecticut
10/2022 - 9/2023

- Managed the preparation and disposal of evening hot meals.
- Assisted customers efficiently during high-demand lunch rush periods.
- Was often praised for my professionalism in Walter Stewart's Market by both employee and manager alike

FedEx Hartford, Connecticut
Package Handler 11/2020 - 6/2021

rackage Hallulei

- Loaded and unloaded 700 packages an hour weighing 10 lbs 50lbs in a fast paced work environment
- Established flexible workflow to accommodate teamwork in completing unloading and loading truck tasks
- Managed belt operations to promote a smooth workflow to team members within the area

EDUCATION

Flatiron School Remote

Full Stack Web Development, Python with Flask and JavaScript program

07/2023 - 02/2024

Eastern Connecticut State University

Completed credits toward Bachelor of Science in Computer Science
Computer Science and Programming I & II, Fundamentals of Computing, JAVA, C++

Willimantic, Connecticut 6/2019 - 1/2021